

Muhammed Safvan P

React.js Developer





About Me

I'm a Self-taught React.js Developer. I have completed a real time project which is a Cricket Club's website including almost the Club's activities, players etc. and also have included an E-commerce section for sale the Cricket equipment, with node.js as backend and HBS as frontend. As React, I had participated in a major ecommerce Project with Reactjs as frontend and which is done by django as it's server side language. I have experienced in some another tools like Redux, Redux toolkit, Material UI, Canva and Figma as well.

Education Background

GPTC (Government Polytechnic College , Perinthalmanna)

During 08/2017 - 06/2020

Diploma in Electronics Engineering

Projects

CENTURY UNIVERSAL - CUCC

CENTURY UNIVERSAL is a cricket club's web application playing under Malappuram District Cricket Association (MDCA), and which having two phases, user and Admin. Here User can buy the Cricket accessories and add their details if they are a Player of Century Universal . and apply coupons whenever they need. Admin can manage All users , shopping as well as the Products and add the Umpires and Officials of CUCC and, also add the upcoming Events and News as well at any time.

Key features -

- Bcrypt
- Cloudinary
- Multer
- Twilio
- Razorpay
- Sweetalert

My Contact



muhammedsafvan1ms@gmail.com



+91 75588-64266



Malappuram dt. Kerala , India zip: 679341



http://mdsafvan.tech



https://github.com/safvanms

Skills

- Javascript
- React.js
- Redux
- · API integration
- HTML5
- CSS3
- Bootstrap 4 & 5
- Material UI

Familiar With

- Canva
- Figma
- Git actions
- Node.js
- AJAX
- ¡Query

Languages

- Malayalam
- English
- Tamil
- Hindi
- Urdu
- Arabic (read)

Work Experience

React.js Developer

from 10/2021 - Present

I was a self taught MERN stack developer and having been keen interest in the frontend .So I'd chosen the React , the modern and most popular library of Javascript , as the frontend language. I've done a lot of mini project with React js as well as Redux and a huge Participation for a main Project (full stack) in it's frontend , and also have done a project with MERN.

KIML (Kyungshin Industrial Motherson Ltd)

04/2021 - 08/2021Machine operator

Even though I started working as a Machine Operator, later I understood the fact that, that was not my real way and passion as well, so I just continued the coding wherever I quit. Eventually I could learn more about it and I chose to be in this field and make it as my career either.

• e-cart

e-cart is an an e-commerce website using Reactjs as it's frontend and Python django as it's backend. Here the website includes fully functionalities of an e-commerce website such as Cart, Payments etc. It's having two phases as Admin and User as well. Throughout the project I had used Redux and Redux toolkit for the better UI.

Frontend

- Reactis
- Redux
- Redux-toolkit

Backend

• Python django

Mini Projects

• **Todo App** using Reactis





• **Portfolio** using Reactjs





Redux-mini projects

Redux toolkit Redux Thunk etc.

Declaration

I hereby declare that all the information furnished above are true and correct to the best of my knowledge

- Muhammed Safvan P